# WILLIAM DIFP

■ WillWebDesigns@gmail.com

www.williamdiep.me

SF Bay Area, CA

in www.linkedin.com/in/wdiep

Software Developer with an appreciation and eye for good design, and knowledgeable of full development cycle (design, development, and deployment).

Background includes seven years of experience in systems administration and tech support, and ten years of experience in teaching and mentoring. Recent positions include providing customercentric tier 1 and 2 support with scopes of project management and consulting services. Passion for contributing to open source, learning new technologies, and teaching

# Skills

HTML5/CSS3

SASS

JavaScript/ES6

**jQuery** 

AJAX

**Templating Engines** 

Webpack

Gulp

Bootstrap 4

Foundation 6

Python

Git

**MVC** Architecture

Content Management Systems

Responsive Web Design

Search Engine Optimization

Google Analytics

MailChimp

Adobe Photoshop

Responsive HTML Emails

**BEM Methodology** 

Django

PostgreSQL

NodeJS

Express

MongoDB

Linux

Digital Ocean

Amazon Web Services

Nginx

Apache

# **Education**

#### San Jose State University

Bachelor of Science Health Science 2013 GPA 3.4/4.0

#### Foothill College

Associate of Science Computer Science 2018 GPA 3.85/4.0

## Front End Developer Code Camp (Cañada College)

2016

Enrolled in a 16-week immersive training program learning front-end programming, data structures, algorithms, & agile development

Collaborated in agile teams to plan and create websites and web apps

# **Experience**

#### theCoderSchool

Coding Instructor

San Jose & Fremont, CA · Jul 2017

 Instruct and mentor 6 - 16 year olds web development, game development, and data structures and algorithms using HTML5/ CSS3, JavaScript, and Python

#### Will's Web Designs

Full Stack Developer

SF Bay Area, CA · May 2016 to Current

- · Design, develop, and deploy full stack responsive web apps and websites for startups and small businesses
- Consult with clients, provide scope of project, proposals, and statement of work

#### **NASA Ames Research Center**

Mountain View, CA · Jul 2013 to Oct 2013

Junior Graphic & Web Content Manager (Intern)

- Generated, revised and, managed webpages for the Earth Science Division using HTML5, CSS3, and Javascript. Improved web usability while providing administrative support to senior team members
- Collaboratively worked in a team of four to effectively create over 25 high-quality designs of brochures, posters, and presentations using Microsoft Office Suite and Adobe Photoshop in an aggressive one-month time-frame resulting an increase of \$28K funding
- Coached four interns on a 1-1 basis on using Microsoft Office Suite, Adobe Photoshop, & Adobe Illustrator increasing team efficiency by ten fold

#### GoFundMe

Redwood City, CA · Aug 2016 to Nov 2016

IT Administrator (Contract)

 Sole technician who provided technical support and systems administration to 100+ users in new office supporting executives, finance, marketing, and engineering departments

## DominoComp Technology Source

San Jose, CA · Sep 2014 to Jan 2016

IT Support Specialist

- Provided tier 1 and 2 software and hardware support locally and remotely to 100+ clients
- Reduced help desk calls by 30% by developing end-user training and knowledge database

#### Citi's Sleepworld

San Jose, CA · Jun 2011 to Sep 2014

IT & Customer Services Support

- Provided desktop support and trained 25 staffs the efficiently use of business systems and peripherals improving weekly shipments by double
- Handled customer inquiries, billing concerns, service requests, and issued return merchandise authorizations

# Foothill-De Anza Community College District

Cupertino, CA · Aug 2009 to Jun 2011